William Hobart Royce Papers
William Hobart Royce Papers
- Printed material
  - Samõez, João Gaspar (Box 33)
  - San Lazzaro, G. Di (Box 33)
  - Sanborn, Alvan F. (Royce catalog number: R3728) (Box 33)
  - Sand, George/"Aurora" (Box 34)
  - Sanders, Mary F. (Royce catalog number: R3731, R3732) (Box 34)
  - Sanvoisin, Gaëtan (Box 34)
  - Sargent, George H. (Box 34)
  - Saulnier, Albert (Box 34)
  - Saunier, Charles (Royce catalog number: R3741) (Box 34)
  - Saurat, Denis (Box 34)
  - Savary, Léon (Box 34)
  - Schaffer, Aaron (Royce catalog number: R3747) (Box 34)
  - Schalbert, Edwin (Box 34)
  - Schell, Stanley (Royce catalog number: R3748) (Box 34)
  - Scherer, Edmond (Royce catalog number: R1168) (Box 34)
  - Schewirekki, Stephen (Royce catalog number: R3749) (Box 34)
  - Schinz, Albert (Box 34)
  - Schneider, Louis (Box 34)
  - Schneider, Gustave (Box 34)
  - Scott, Mary W. (Royce catalog number: R3755) (Box 34)
  - Séché, Alphonse, and Bertrant, Jules (Royce catalog number: R3757) (Box 34)
  - Séché, Léon (Royce catalog number: R3759, R3760) (Box 34)
  - Seillière, Ernest (Royce catalog number: R3773) (Box 34)
  - Sergines (Box 34)
  - Serval, Maurice (Royce catalog number: R3779, R3780 ) (Box 34)
  - "Serviteur du Livre, Le" (Box 34)
  - Sexagenus (Box 34)
  - Shanks, Lewis Piaget (Royce catalog number: R3786) (Box 34)
  - Scherer, J.W. (Royce catalog number: R3788, R3789, R3790) (Box 35)
  - Shermund[cartoon] (Box 35)
  - Shinn, Charles Howard (Royce catalog number: R3791) (Box 35)
  - Shipley, Joseph T. (Box 35)
  - Showerman, Grant (Royce catalog number: R3792) (Box 35)
  - Silvio (Box 35)
  - Simon, P.-Max (Box 35)
  - Slocombe, George (Royce catalog number: R3797) (Box 35)
  - Smith, Harry L.[empty envelope] (Royce catalog number: S5606A) (Box 35)
  - Smith, Katherin Augusta (Royce catalog number: R3800) (Box 35)
  - Smith, Pat (Box 35)
  - Sordet, Dominique (Box 35)
  - Souday, Paul (Royce catalog number: R3809, R3811, R3812, R3813) (Box 35)
  - Speicher, Eugène (Royce catalog number: R3816) (Box 35)
  - Spencer, Edwina (Royce catalog number: R3817) (Box 35)
  - Spent, Henry (Box 35)
  - Spoelberch de Lovenjoul, Vte de (Royce catalog number: R3820, R3837, R3840, R3841, R3843, R3844, R3845, R3846 ), 2 folders (Box 35)
  - Stallings, Lawrence (Royce catalog number: R3849) (Box 35)
  - Stanley, Hiram M. (Royce catalog number: R3850) (Box 35)
  - Stany (Box 35)
  - Steell, Willis (Box 35)
  - Stein, Esther (Box 35)
  - Stephen, Leslie (Royce catalog number: R3854) (Box 35)
  - Stern, Alfred (Box 36)
  - Strachey, J. St. Loe (Royce catalog number: R3856) (Box 36)
  - Strauss, Harold (Box 36)
  - Strazzarino, Hector (Box 36)
  - Strowski, Fortunat (Box 36)
  - Stutchbury, Harold O. (Box 36)
  - Suzini, Germaine (Box 36)
  - Suzini, Jean (Box 36)
  - Symons, Arthur (Royce catalog number: R3863, R3864, R3865) (Box 36)
  - Syracuse University Library Associates, 1958-1959; 3 issues of the Courier (Box 36)
  - Taft, Lyman W. (Box 36)
  - Tailhade, Laurent (Royce catalog number: R3868) (Box 36)
  - Talmeyr, Maurice (Royce catalog number: R3871, R3872) (Box 36)
  - Tauber, Paul (Box 36)
  - Tazelaar, Marguerite (Box 36)
  - Tenenbaum, Joshua (Shea) (Box 36)
  - Tharaud, Jérô et Jean (Box 36)
  - Théolleyne, Jean-Marc (Royce catalog number: R3893) (Box 36)
  - Thiébault-Sisson (Box 36)
  - Thierry, Georges (Box 36)
  - Thomas, Jacques (Box 36)
  - Thompson, Charles Willis (Royce catalog number: R3888) (Box 36)
  - Thornton, Hermann H. (Box 36)
  - Tian, Renzo (Box 36)
  - Tild, Jean (Box 36)
  - Tinker, Edward-Laroque (Box 37)
  - Tirand, Max (Royce catalog number: R3893) (Box 37)
  - Toldo, Pietro (Royce catalog number: R3894) (Box 37)
  - Treich, Leon (Box 37)
  - Treizc, Les (Box 37)
  - Trent, William Peterfield (Royce catalog number: R3919, R3920, R3921) (Box 37)
  - Truc, Gonzague (Box 37)
  - Truillot, A. (Box 37)
  - Tuckerman, H.J. (Royce catalog number: R3922) (Box 37)
  - Tuttle, A.H. (Royce catalog number: R3923) (Box 37)
  - Unt, V. (Box 37)
  - Urteaga, Franklin (Box 37)
  - Uzanne, Octave (Royce catalog number: R3929, R3933) (Box 37)
  - Valerio, Edith (Royce catalog number: R3937, R3938) (Box 37)
  - Vandérem, Fernand (Royce catalog number: R3940) (Box 37)
  - Van Gelder, Robert (Box 37)
  - Vandoyer, Jean-Louis (Box 37)
  - Vaulx, Bernard de (Box 37)
  - Vautel, Clément (Box 37)
  - Vauzelles, Ludovic de (Box 37)
  - Verne, Maurice (Box 37)
  - Vidal, Maurice (Box 37)
  - Viguez, Édouard (Box 37)
  - Vivian, Herbert (Box 37)
  - Vivier, Michel (Box 37)
  - Walbridge, Earle F. (Box 37)
  - Wallquist, Örjan (Box 37)
  - Walpole, Sir Hugh (Box 37)
  - Walton, Edith H. (Box 37)
  - Weadock, Louis (Royce catalog number: R3975) (Box 37)
  - Wenger, Jared (Box 37)
  - Werveke, Jan (Royce catalog number: 2416) (Box 37)
  - Werth, Alexander (Box 37)
  - West, Anthony (Box 37)
  - Westrum, A.S. Van (Royce catalog number: R3980) (Box 37)
  - White, Robert (Box 37)
  - Williams, Talcott (Royce catalog number: R3984) (Box 37)
  - Wittfogel, K.A. (Box 38)
  - Woodlock, Thomas F. (Box 38)
  - Worthington, Hugh S. (Royce catalog number: R3988) (Box 38)
  - Wyzewa, Théodore de (Royce catalog number: R3991) (Box 38)
  - Xan, Fernand (Box 38)
  - Yanitelli, Victor R. (Box 38)
  - Ybbarra, J.R. (Box 38)
  - Yeats, William Butler (Box 38)
  - Yerly, Robert (Box 38)
  - Young, Stanley (Box 38)
  - Zabludovski, Mikhail (Box 38)
  - Zagorski, M. (Box 38)
  - Zavaes, Alexandre (Box 38)
  - Ziman, H.D. (Box 38)
  - Zimand, Roman (Box 38)
  - Zweig, Stefan [2nd folder: unrevised proofs of Zweig's "Balzac"], 2 folders (Box 38)
- Writings
  - Books
    - A Balzac Bibliography, 6 folders; draft (Box 64)
    - A Balzac Bibliography, 5 folders; draft (Box 65)
    - A Balzac Bibliography, 6 folders; draft, notebook, galleys, addenda (Box 66)
    - A Balzac Bibliography [Additional Material], 5 folders (Box 67)
    - A Balzac Bibliography [Additional Material], 6 folders (Box 68)
    - A Balzac Bibliography [Additional Material], 5 folders (Box 69)
    - A Balzac Bibliography (Epitome) (Oversize 1)
    - A Balzac Bibliography, title page draft (Box 69)
    - "Suggested Outline for Analysis of the Topical Index of A Balzac Bibliography", hand written draft (Box 69)
    - "Outline for Analysis of the Topical Index of A Balzac Bibliography", 5 folders; several drafts (Box 70)
    - "Indexes to a Balzac Bibliography", 4 folders (Box 70)
    - Index cards for topical index (Oversize 10)
    - Index cards for topical index (Oversize 11)
    - Index cards [large] (Box 90)
    - Works of Balzac [introduction], 4 folders (Box 70)
    - "Works of Balzac. Note of Explanation to Map of Balzac's Human Comedy" (Box 71)
    - A Balzac Bibliography [notebooks] (Box 71)
    - Notebooks (Box 71)
    - [First] Supplement to a Balzac Bibliography, 4 folders; hand written draft (Box 71)
    - [First] Supplement to a Balzac Bibliography, 5 folders; hand written draft (Box 72)
    - [First] Supplement to a Balzac Bibliography, 5 folders; hand written draft (Box 73)
    - [First] Supplement to a Balzac Bibliography, 6 folders; hand written draft (Box 74)
    - [First] Supplement to a Balzac Bibliography, 6 folders; notes, clippings, and note cards (Box 75)
  - Bulletin of the Balzac Society
    - Material for no 13 to 15, 3 folders (Box 75)
    - Material for no 16 to 21, 5 folders (Box 76)
    - Material for no 22 to 25, 3 folders (Box 77)
    - Drafts of Bulletin no 1-10 (Box 77)
    - Printer's copies (Box 77)
    - Proof sheets (Box 77)
    - Issues no 1-35, 1940-1962 (Box 77)
  - Chapter
    - Chapter on Balzac in D.C. Cabeen's A Critical Bibliography of French Literature (Box 77)
  - Essays
    - "Balzac", in the American Society of the French Legion of Honor magazine (Box 77)
    - "Balzac: An Appreciation", 2 folders (Box 77)
    - "Balzac as He Should Be Read", 2 folders (Box 77)
    - "Balzac as He Was Not", 2 folders (Box 78)
    - "Balzac Bibliography with a Purpose", 3 folders (Box 78)
    - "Balzac en Amérique" (Box 78)
    - "Balzac, Immortal", 2 folders (Box 78)
    - "Balzac, Immortal", scrapbook (Oversize 7)
    - "Balzac in Bay Ridge", 20 folders; Essay series in "The Brooklyn Spectator" (Box 78)
    - "Balzac in Bay Ridge", scrapbook (Oversize 8)
    - "Notes on Rare Books" (Box 78)
    - "Balzac Receives an Envoy", 2 folders (Box 78)
    - "Balzac Receives an Envoy", 4 folders (Box 79)
    - "A Balzac Renaissance" (Box 79)
    - "Balzac, the Galley Slave", 2 folders (Box 79)
    - "Chronological Order of La Comédie Humaine" (Box 79)
    - Description of "Le Decret des Ruggeri," an "assembly of 52 manuscript pages and printer's proofs", hand written (Box 79)
    - "Dilettante" (Box 79)
    - "Great Anniversaries: Balzac", 4 folders (Box 79)
    - "How Balzac Wrested Fame from Failure" (Box 79)
    - "Le bibliographe de Balzac" (Box 79)
    - "My Ember in the Bonfire of Fame", published in the series "The Seasons Greetings from Balzac and Royce" (Box 79)
    - "An Unpublished Letter of Balzac", 2 folders (Box 79)
    - "Why Fine Bindings?", 2 folders (Box 79)
  - By others
    - Anonymous, Balzac bibliography, French; in card form; Henry Goulet, éditeur, Paris (Box 79)
    - Barquet, Nicolás, "Gayarre: El cantante de la voz de oro", English title: "Gayarre: The Singer with the Golden Voice" (Box 79)
    - Baudelaire, Charles, Selections from "Paris Spleen", translated by Louise Varèse (Box 79)
    - Brereton, Geoffrey, "Paul Valéry", from his Introduction to the French Poets (Box 79)
    - Bouteron, Marcel, "Balzac et le conseil du Roi," and "Bedouck!", 2 folders (Box 79)
    - Cohen, Rubin, "Balzac in the U.S. During the 19th Century" (Box 79)
    - Cohen, Rubin, "Balzac in the U.S. During the 19th Century" (Box 80)
    - Gastaldi, Santiago, "La Comedia Humana. Analisis de su contento sociólogico y artistico" (Box 80)
    - Hastings, Walter Scott, "Balzac and Souverain," "Balzac," "Maria", 3 folders; galley proofs of "Balzac" (Box 80)
    - Le Courtois, Claude, "L'art de la nouvelle chez Balzac" (Box 80)
    - Middleton, George, "That was Balzac" (Box 80)
    - Ronai, Paul [?], "L'Israélite: An Early Work of Balzac" (Box 80)
    - Stutchbury, Harold Owen, parts of his Chronological Bibliography of Balzac and Balzac's Autobiography (Box 80)
    - Swinburne, Algernon Charles, Lesbia Brandon, photostat copy of the portion of his unpublished novel that mentions Balzac (Box 80)
    - Weiner, L., Balzac and His Times, 3 folders (Box 80)
    - Weiner, L., Balzac and His Times (Box 81)
    - Wist, Ki, "le travail de Balzac" (Box 81)
    - French articles on Balzac, type written; Ex Libris Walter Scott Hastings (Box 81)
    - Reviews of Royce's Balzac Bibliography (Box 81)
    - Le Messager de New York, 8 issues (Box 81)
    - Poem by anonymous, "Balzac: Hommage à Auguste Rodin" (Box 81)
    - Poems by Angelo, Alfred Antoine Furman, Théo, and Gaston Prinet (Box 81)
    - Poem by Lewys, Georges, "Britannia, Britannia Forever!", 1941; with an autograph dedication by the author to Royce (Oversize 1)
  - Royce's poetry and other items
    - Poems under the pseudonyms "Cassandra," "Colonel Philippe Bridau," "Pennmore", 4 folders; "Pennmore" is subdivided in "general" and "war poems" (Box 81)
    - General, 1925-1943; 3 folders (Box 81)
    - General, 1944-1960; 5 folders; incl. undated poems (Box 82)
    - War poems, 1940-1946; 5 folders; incl. undated war poems (Box 82)
    - Poem drafts, 3 folders (Box 82)
    - Compilations of Royce's poems (Box 82)
    - Sonnets of a Bibliographer (Box 82)
    - Novel draft [?], unfinished (Box 82)
  - Translations by Royce
    - Alain, "With Balzac" (Box 82)
    - Balzac translations, 5 folders (Box 83)
    - Balzac translations, 9 folders (Box 84)
    - Balzac translations, 4 folders (Box 85)
    - Béguin, Albert, "Balzac Visionaire", 2 folders; English title: "Balzac the Visionary" (Box 85)
    - Benedek, Marcel, "Balzac" (Box 85)
    - Benjamin, René, "La prodigieuse vie d'Honoré de Balzac", English title: "The Prodigious Life of Honoré de Balzac" (Box 85)
    - Bouteron, Marcel, "Le culte de Balzac dans le monde", "Études Balzaciennes", 3 folders; English titles: "The Cult of Balzac in the World", "Balzac Studies" (Box 85)
    - Curtius, Ernst Robert, "Balzac" (Box 86)
    - Ducourneau, Jean A., "An Unpublished Work of Balzac - Le Réclamiste (The Puffer)" (Box 86)
    - Evans, Henri, Review of Hunt, Herbert J. "Honoré de Balzac. A Biography" and "Balzac's Comédie Humaine", 1959 (Box 86)
    - Flat, Paul, Essais sur Balzac, 2 folders; English title: Essays on Balzac (Box 86)
    - Gauthier, Henri, "The Usurer in three Works of Balzac", 2 folders (Box 86)
    - Le Breton, André, L'homme et I'oeuvre, English title: Balzac: The Man and His Work (Box 86)
    - Lindgren, Hellen "Honoré de Balzac", 1900; essay in "Skalder och Tänkare: Litterära Essayer", pages 307-339, transl. by Eda M. Royce (Box 86)
    - Métadier, B. Paul, "A Great Invalid Misunderstood", Jan 1958 (Box 86)
    - Picon, Gaeton, [preface to?] "Illusions perdues", Jan 1958; English title: "The 'Lost Illusions' or Hope Recovered" (Box 86)
    - Mercure de France, Jan 1958; from which Royce translated the essays by Métadier and Picon (Box 86)
    - Pommier, Jean, "About the First Edition of Louis Lambert", Oct 1959 (Box 86)
    - Rónai, Pál [Paul], "Jegyzetek Honoré de Balzac Fiatalkori Regényeihez", 1930; English title: "Notes to the Oeuvres de jeunesse of Honoré de Balzac". Budapest: Rónai Miksa Könyvkereskedése (Oversize 9)
    - Sandeau, M. Jules, "The Last Fairy", accompanied by "The Life and Misfortunes of Horace de Saint-Aubin" (Box 86)
    - Thun-Hohenstein, Graf Paul, "Die Novelle von Balzac", 1930-1931 (Box 86)
    - Zweig, Stefan "Balzac," from Három Mester. Balzac, Dickens, Dosztojevszkij, Translation from the German Drei Meister [?] (Box 86)
    - Translation fragment of unknown origin (Box 86)
  - Miscellany
    - Photostat of a "Map of Balzac's Human Comedy" (Oversize 4)
    - Advertisements for Royce's Balzac publications (Box 86)
    - Announcement of the name change from "Les Études Balzaciennes" to "L'Année Balzacienne", hand written draft (Box 86)
    - Announcement of the publication of the definitive edition of Balzac's works, hand written draft (Box 86)
    - "Balzac and the College Girl," "The College Girl and Balzac", lecture in 2 parts (Box 86)
    - Balzac: bibliographic citations for David C. Cabeen's A Critical Bibliography of the 19th Century (Box 86)
    - Balzac: bibliographic citations for David C. Cabeen's A Critical Bibliography of the 19th Century (Box 87)
    - "The Balzac Library of W.H. Royce", 2 folders (Box 87)
    - Balzac, "Le secret des Ruggieri", type written description of a collection of 52 manuscripts and printer's proofs (Box 87)
    - Calendar of the life of Balzac, 1819-1828; 3 folders; 2 drafts (Box 87)
    - List of Balzac editions (Box 87)
    - List of "Royce's Contributions Published in Bruno's 'Life in Letters'" (Box 87)
    - Note on the introduction to "Balzac's Masterpieces", Here, Royce claims that the introduction was actually written by him but he withdrew his name after it was "garbled". (Box 87)
    - "Old Book Table Dinner", 12 Dec 1935; speech (Box 87)
    - Royce's annotations to "Balzac and his Publisher Souverain" (Box 87)
    - "Unpublished Table of the Literary Order" [of Balzac's works] (Box 87)
- Memorabilia
  - Clippings
    - Anonymous about Royce in the American Collector, 1927; presumably written by Charles Heartman (Box 87)
    - Concerning Auguste Geraldi, Geraldi was a Balzacien and publisher e.g. of Royce's poems (Box 87)
    - Concerning Royce, 8 folders (Box 87)
    - Concerning Royce (Box 88)
    - Printed obituaries concerning Royce's death (Box 88)
    - Transcript of an article in the Norwich Bulletin about a Balzac lecture by Royce (Box 88)
    - Stefan Zweig on Royce (Box 88)
  - Family
    - Legal and financial, 2 folders (Box 88)
    - Renewal of Mrs. Royce's subscription to the Brooklyn Academy of Arts, Music and Science, 1934 (Box 88)
    - Clippings concerning the Royce family (Box 88)
    - Genealogy, 4 folders (Box 88)
    - Autographs of the Royce family (Box 88)
  - Photographs, pictures, etc.
    - Two drawings in pencil signed by Marcel Bouteron (Box 88)
    - Royce 'hoody portrait' (Box 88)
    - Royce (Box 88)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 88)
    - 5th Anniversary Dinner of Le Messager de New York (Oversize 5)
    - Drawings of Royce, 3 items (Oversize 4)
    - Photograph of Royce, by Berenice Abbott (Oversize 5)
  - Radio appearances
    - Royce on the radio, 22 May 1945; 27 Mar 1946,; 22 May 1949; 3 folders (Box 88)
  - Miscellany
    - Clippings concerning George Middleton (Box 88)
    - Dinner in honor of César Birotteau (Box 88)
    - Dinner in honor of the conferring of the medal of the Légion d'Honneur to Royce (Box 88)
    - Invitation to the 5th anniversary of Le Messager de New York (Box 88)
    - Note about a monk from Portugal (Box 88)
    - Note on an event commemorating Royce's 70th birthday (Box 88)
    - Numeroscope for Royce (Box 88)
    - Portrait of Gabriel Wells, Royce's employer (Box 89)
    - Program of the 9th Annual Banquet of the Bookseller's League, 10 Feb 1904 (Box 89)
    - Reviews etc., concerning Royce's Balzac Bibliography (Box 89)
    - Royce, membership cards (Box 89)
    - Diploma of Royce's honorary membership of the Centro Literario-Filosofico "Arca del Sur" of Uruguay, 15 Jul 1951 (Oversize 4)
    - Diploma of Royce's membership of the French Legion of Honor and membership medals, 09 Oct 1935 (Oversize 5)
    - Various materials (Box 89)
    - List of "The First/Second Hundred Greatest Names in Literature" (Oversize 1)
    - Announcement diploma of a "Fête Romantique" by the City of Issoudun, France related to the citizenship award for W.H. Royce, 29 Jun 1930; parchment (Oversize 1)
    - "Honoré de Balzac. La Comédie Humaine au Jardin de la France", original engravings by Ferdinand Dubreuil, text by Roland Engerand (Oversize 2)
    - Index card catalogs (Box 90)
Selected index to correspondence
Aubrée, Etienne 1944 1945 1946
Baldensberger, Fernand 1934 1943
Bédé, Jean-Albert
Bouteron, Marcel 1925-1926 1926-1928 1928-1930 1930-1932 1932-1933 1933-1934 1934-1936 1936-1939 1939-1942 1942-1946 1947-1949 1949-1950
Cahoon, Herbert 1957
Chauncerel, André 1929
Crain, William L. 1927 1928 1930 1930 1931 1950 1950
Dargan, Edwin Preston 1922--1926 1926-1928 1928-1930 1930-1932 1932-1933 1933-1934 1934-1936 1936-1937
Furman, Alfred A. 1929
Gastaldi, Santiago 1930-1932 1932-1933 1933-1934 1934-1936 1936-1939 1939-1942 1942-1946 1947-1949 1949-1950 1950-1952 1953-1960
Gould, Charles (University of Bristol) 1952 1953-1959
Haas, J. (Tübingen University, Germany) 1927-1928 1928-1929
Hastings, Walter Scott 1921-1928 1928-1930
Hennion, Horace 1948 1951 1951
Henriquez, Jack [Jaques, pseud. Ki Wist] 1939 1939 1950 1950-1952 1953-1959
Hunt, Herbert J. 1957-60
Lecuyer, Maurice A. (Yale) 1952
Middleton, George 1939 1939 1944
Pommier, Jean 1949 1949 1958
Preston, Ethel 1927
Ritti, Paul 1923-1926 1926-1928 1928-1930 1930-1932 1932-1933 1933-1934 1934-1936 1936-1939 1939-1942 1942-1946 1947-1949 1949-1950 1950-1952
Ronai, Paul (Paulo) 1930 1931 1938 1957
Rottenberg, Max M. 1930
Tenenbaum, Shea (Joshua) 1950 1950-1951
Wodrada, Helen Elcessor Barnes 1923, 1924 1934 1934, 1936 1936, 1939 1939
Zweig, Stefan 1939 1939-1940